<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Ramzy Al Amine</title>
    <link>https://ramzyalamine.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Ramzy Al Amine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://ramzyalamine.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A metric for the degree to which players are playing up to their talent (Part I)</title>
      <link>https://ramzyalamine.com/posts/nba-distance-to-potential/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramzyalamine.com/posts/nba-distance-to-potential/</guid>
      <description>A metric for the degree to which players are playing up to their talent Rolling average of VORP over the last 10 games divided by the highest 10-game rolling VORP average over the course of this player’s 3 most recent seasons.
How would this be useful? This metric would capture just how much a given player is performing relative to their own potential. This metric is intended to measure the degree to which a team is making use of a given player.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flow over talent</title>
      <link>https://ramzyalamine.com/posts/nba-flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramzyalamine.com/posts/nba-flow/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Flow&amp;rdquo; over talent Only a handful a players possess the talent level that is unaffected by the team environment (e.g. LeBron, KD, probably Embiid). The majority of players depend on the opportunity that is provided.
The analytics community vastly over-emphasizes individual ability as a determinant of success. Rightly so, teams hire analysts to help them identify undercover talent.
For the majority players, individual performance depends much more on role, fit, and opportunity, than it does on their own ability level.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
